Professional and personal papers of Edwin Wolf 2nd LCP.EW2
Library Company of Philadelphia
- I. Personal papers, Bulk, 1920-1948; 1798-1991
  - Writings: Incomplete pieces of fiction by Edwin, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Writings: Fiction and poetry by Edwin ("Edwin's ancient writings"), etchings, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Maps, annotated with crayon, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Clippings (includes photocopies of Wolf's obituaries) and curriculum vitae, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Realia, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Personal library: L'Anti-Justine ou Les Delices de L'Amour, 1798 (Volume 1)
  - Personal library: Lippincott's First Reader (pornographically extra-illustrated), 1911, 1981 (Volume 2)
  - Personal library: Baby book, 1911-1913 (Volume 3)
  - Personal library: In Memory of Minnie Hirsh, 1868-1923 (Volume 4)
  - Personal library: The Blake-Linell Accounts in the Library of Yale University, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Personal library: Family Bible, 1955 (Volume 5)
  - Personal library: Oeuvres, by Francoise Villon, 1973 (Volume 6)
  - Personal library: Three Quarters of a Centennial, 1986 December 6 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Personal library: "The Donald F. Hyde Award of Princeton University" gift book, 1988 (Volume 7)
  - Personal library: Catalogue of Edwin Wolf's collection of classical literature, including printed inventory and index cards, circa 1990 (Box 39)
  - Family: Certificate for 50 shares of Specie Bass Mining Company, 1867 May 9 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Family: Art projects by the Wolf children, circa 1945 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Family: Pencil and crayon drawing, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Family, Edwin Wolf I: Letters, photographs, notebook, 1878, 1890, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Family, Morris Wolf: Invitations and letter, 1910, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Family, Morris Wolf: Letter from W. J. Deacon, 1928 August 1 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Family, Morris Wolf: Clippings and obituaries of Edwin Wolf I, 1934, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Family, Morris Wolf: Log of family expenses, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Family, Morris Wolf: Eulogy and executor certificate for Rose Hirsh Wolf, 1951, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Family, Morris Wolf: Speech given in honor of Morris Wolf's 80th birthday, 1973 August 20 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Family, Morris Wolf: Photographs, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Family, Morris Wolf: Poetry, plays, and other writings, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Family, Morris Wolf: Sketches of family crests, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Family, Margaret Dannenbaum Wolf: Painted glass slides, report cards from Oak Lane Country Day School and Bryn Mawr College, letters and exam results from Temple University, 1960-1962 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Family, Margaret Dannenbaum Wolf: Notes on wartime first aid training, interrogatories regarding car accident, 1942, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Family, Ellen Wolf: Report card, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- II. Professional records, Bulk, 1930-1985; 1889-1992
  - IIa. Professional correspondence, 1930-1985
    - Adams, Randolph: 2 letters and a sketch between Edwin and Adams regarding Cotton Mather, 1933 May 20, 1933 October 6 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Adhemar, Jean: To Edwin, 1949 January 20 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Alden, John: 3 letters between Edwin and Alden regarding Edwin's article “Franklin's Way to Wealth” in Philadelphia Forum, 1949 March 21-April 8 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Babb, James T.: To Edwin, 1954 June 1 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Barker, Nicholas: To Edwin, 1972 September 1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Barrett, C. Waller: To Edwin, 1957 November 1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Blanck, Jacob: To Edwin, 1962 October 28 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Boorstin, Daniel: To Edwin, 1969 February 13 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Bowers, Fredson: 8 letters between Edwin and Bowers, 1947 April 11-1949 January 28 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Bowers, Fredson: 9 letters between Edwin and Bowers, 1949 February 1-1949 April 26 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Bowers, Fredson: 6 letters between Edwin and Bowers, 1949 April 28-1951 January 13 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Boyd, Julian P.: To Edwin, 1953 November 9 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Brigham, Clarence S.: 4 letters between Edwin and Brigham, 1953 January 30-1956 August 24 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Butlin, Martin: 2 letters from Edwin, 1974 June 26, 1975 March 25 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Carter, John: To Edwin, 1960 November 8 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Cushing, J. D.: 3 letters between Edwin and Cushing, 1969 October 24-November 8 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Dilworth, R.: 3 letters between Edwin and Dilworth, 1962 February 7-November 1 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Fainsod, Merle: 2 letters between Edwin and Fainsod, 1964 November 18, 1964 November 25 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Fishel, Richard M.: To Edwin, 1947 September 18 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Flower, Desmond: 2 letters between Edwin and Flower, 1937 September 25, 1937 October 21 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Goode, Wilson: To Edwin, 1983 May 13 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Goodhart, Howard L.: 5 letters between Edwin and Goodhart, 1941 September 25-1942 June 16 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Grove, Lee: 2 letters to Edwin, 1961 May 1, 1962 December (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Hakluyt Society: 4 letters between Edwin and Edward Lynam, 1938 June 3-1939 January 14 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Haney, John Louis: 2 letters between Edwin and Haney, 1949 March 30, 1949 March 31 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Hayward, John: 7 letters between Edwin and Hayward, 1959 July 10-1962 March 14 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Hellman, Geoffrey: To Edwin, 1963 February 12 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Hofer, Phillip: To Edwin, 1946 May 3 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Huff, William K.: 8 letters between Edwin and Huff regarding Edwin's article “Franklin's Way to Wealth” in Philadelphia Forum, 1949 January 19-1950 March 21 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Hunter, Dr. Richard: To Edwin, 1966 March 21 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Hyde, Donald: To Edwin, 1963 July 17 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Jackson, William A.: 8 letters between Edwin and Jackson, 1942 May 26-1963 January 21 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Leningrad Library: 9 letters between Edwin and Boris E. Skivirsky, Alexander Fleischer, and Beatrice Heiman, 1935 September 27-1943 September 29 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia: 25 letters between Edwin and the staff (mostly Marie Korey), 1978 August 13-1980 August 12 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia: Letters of congratulations to Edwin from C. K. Shipton, R. Hirsch, Sylvian M. Cohen, and M. Spector (4 items); letters from Wainwright regarding appointment to Library Company (2 items), 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - McManaway, James: 2 letters to Edwin, 1943 March 16, 1943 September 29 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Munby, Dr. A. N. L.: To Edwin, 1971 December 8 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Oates, J.: To Edwin, 1962 August 27 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Parma, Valta: To Edwin, 1937 October 28 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Pantzer, Katherine F.: To Edwin, 1970 June 26 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Perrin, A. L.: 2 letters to Edwin, 1959 June 14, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Phillips, Benjamin (Librarian of Allegheny College): To Edwin with a quotation from a manuscript appended concerning the London Antiquary Society, 1963 January 15 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Powell, John H.: 2 letters to Edwin, 1964 August 4, undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Randall, David A.: To Edwin, 1962 July 27 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Ray, Gordon N.: 3 letters to Edwin, 1962 June 22, 1965 February 23, 1965 March 2 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Rosenwald, Lessing J.: To Edwin, 1941 May 29 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Stern, Thomas: Carbon typescript of Edwin's “How Francis (the Mule) Was Born,” letters between Edwin and Alan Kempner, and letters between Edwin and David and Thomas Stern, 1945 April 30, 1946 February 28-December 19 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Stern, Thomas: 12 letters between Edwin and Stern regarding Edwin's “How Francis (the Mule) Was Born”, 1947 April 14-1948 October 8 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Streeter, Thomas W.: 3 letters between Edwin and Streeter, Anna E. Dougherty, and Charles C. Mish, 1945 June 22-1946 March 4 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Thompson, Lawrence S.: To Edwin, 1970 October 8 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Tighe, Benjamin: To Edwin, 1969 June 30 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Tuchman, Barbara: 3 letters to Edwin, 1984 March 30-1985 September 3 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Valguarnera, Conrad: 2 letters between Rosenbach Company and Valguarnera concerning research services, 1936 October 20, 1930 October 22 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Wagner, Henry R.: 2 letters between Edwin and Wagner, 1939 July 18, 1939 August 8 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Wainwright, Nicholas B.: Letter concerning the memorial written by Edwin for A. S. W. Rosenbach in The Library Chronicle, XIX, 45-50, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - White, Gilbert: 3 letters between Edwin and Gilbert White regarding offering a course in bibliography at Haverford College, 1948 May 10-November 12 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - White, Gilbert: To Edwin, 1952 July 2 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Wolf, Thomas: 2 letters to Edwin, 1966 February 16, 1966 February 22 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Wroth, Lawrence C.: To Edwin, 1943 January 25 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Wylie, J. C: Letters between Edwin and Wylie, photograph from the 1949 meeting of the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1948 July 21-1953 March 24 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Assorted professional correspondence, 1977, 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Miscellaneous persons: 17 letters between Edwin and J. T. Babb, J. Rosenwald, M. J. McKosker, M. Merrell, Wm. H. McCarthy, Madeline Boyd, H. M. Bond, C. A. Stonehill, Henry S. Savage, and W. H. Blumenthal, 1932 November 9-1957 October 23 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Miscellaneous persons: Letters between Edwin and W. L. Fox, J. Whitehill, and E. J. Humeston; schedule for the American Society of Appraisers meeting; invitation to a talk by Edwin at the City History Society of Philadelphia, 1958 April 17-1961 April 1, 1958 April 19, 1958 April 22 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Miscellaneous persons: 17 letters between Edwin and J. David Stern, W. N. Francis, A. D. Wainwright, E. J. Wessen, R. N. Williams, and George Vaux, 1961 April 28-1970 November 16 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - IIb. Professional affiliations, Bulk, 1931-1969; 1889-1992
    - The American Antiquarian Society: Program for lecture and demonstration by Ricky Jay, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - The American Philosophical Society: 1949 Library Bulletin (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - The American Philosophical Society: Correspondence regarding membership, 1974 April-May (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - The American Philosophical Society: Materials regarding Edwin's trip to the 1980 combined meeting of the American Philosophical Society and the Royal Society (12 items), 1980 March-May (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - American Printing History Association: Award acceptance speech, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - The Athenaeum of Philadelphia: Meeting minutes and other records (7 items), 1961 December 18-1971 October 21 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - The Athenaeum of Philadelphia: Meeting minutes and other records (8 items), 1969 May 13-1971 January 14 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia: Member list, 1952 July (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Bicentennial: 5 letters between Edwin and A. B. Lipkin, M. L. Forer, B. Dale Davis, Mrs. D. Slade, and S. M. Cohen; manuscript of an article entitled “A Bicentennial Hailing 1776 Ideals Urged,” The Evening Bulletin; facsimile of the Declaration of Rights made by the colonial Virginia legislators, 1970 December 12-December 24, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Community Free Library Association: Bookmark; address by R. D. Compton on assuming the Presidency of the association; 2 letters to Edwin from R. D. Compton; list of Board of Directors; photostat of "Goals for National Library Week in Pennsylvania, 1961", 1961, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Elkins Park Free Library: Letter calling for community support; accounts for 1958, 1958 May (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Franklin Inn Club: 11 letters between Edwin and John Lewis, Russel Smith, J. A. McKaugham, Graeme Lorimer, and J. McCosker, 1947 June 2-1949 March 22 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Franklin Inn Club: Letters between Edwin and John F. Lewis, M. K. Whitehead, E. S. Gifford, D. Dale Davis, M. K. Whiteleather, R. Spiller, and C. C. Bowman; addresses to members by Claude C. Bowman [Christmas Lunch, 1959], and Edwin [William Waite Dinner, 19 January 1962]., 1953 February 23-1969 February 5, 1959 December, 1962 January 19 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Franklin Institute: Certificate of membership, 1954 September (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Free Library of Philadelphia: 9 letters between Edwin and E. H. Erskine, Emerson Greenaway, J. S. Clark, and J. F. Lewis regarding Edwin's tenure on the Board of Directors, 1946, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Friends of the Free Library and Baltimore Bibliophiles: Letters to Edwin from Mrs. R. McCoy and Frank N. James, 1960 December 10, 1960 December 22 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - The Grolier Club of New York: Letters between Edwin and E. Naumberg, A. Davidson, C. Waller Barrett, and F. M. A. McCorison; invitation from the Houghtons and Hydes; plan and program for 75th Anniversary Excursion, 1959 January 21-1965 September 23, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - The Grolier Club of New York: Invitations, programs, notes regarding various events in London, England, 1959 April-1959 May (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Guggenheim Fellowhip: Acknowledgement of receipt of Edwin's application; list of 1957 appointments; letters to Edwin from H. Allen Moe, Gordon N. Ray, and Josephine Leighton, circa 1957, 1961 March 31, 1961 April 21, 1961 June 8 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - J. C. Brown, Library Associates: Letter to Edwin from R. Dechert; “The Century of Wise Scholarship” by Marjorie Jones, reprinted from Pembroke Alumna, 1963 January, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia: Anniversary memorabilia, including Last Will and Testament of James Rush, title page to original articles of association, 204th and 205th annual reports, letters to shareholders, 1889, 1894, 1935, 1936, 1937 October 7, 1939 April 8 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia: Anniversary memorabilia, including letters to members and shareholders, 200th anniversary report, guide to exhibition of bicentennial celebration, Bulletin of the Library Company of Philadelphia, 1929 April 24, 1931, 1932 April 21, 1933 April-June, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia: "Notes on the concept and operation of the Rare Book Collection, in re the Library Company of Philadelphia" report, 1952 August 20, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia: Notes and reports regarding surveys of the Ridgeway Library and the collections of the Library Company of Philadelphia, 1952, 1953, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia: Correspondence regarding Philadelphia Asylum Plate, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia: Guestbook for "A Pride of Acquisitions, 1953-1978", 1978 March 3 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia: "Library Company of Philadelphia as a museum" notes and transcriptions, circa 1980s, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia: Certificate from Governor Robert P. Casey to the Library Company for 250th anniversary, 1992 March 25 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia: Reproductions of map prints, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript Society: Letter to Edwin from D. H. Coblentz, 1962 October 25 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - The Modern Language Association of America: Letters between Edwin and P. W. Long and Lynam R. Bradley, 1942 September 22, 1942 September 23 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - National Geographical Society: Certificate of election, 1920 November 13 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - New Jersey Library Association: Letters between Edwin and Frederick T. Davies, F. T. Davies, Edna Miriam (Hoopes), Otto Eisenschiml, and H. B. Hough; application for the Saint David Society, 1938 April 4-April 21 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Penn Athletics Club: 5 letters between Edwin and Mrs. Lewis Gibbs, 1941 October 31-November 19 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Philadelphia, City of: Citation form Mayor W. Wilson Goode to Edwin Wolf II for service on Mayor's Cultural Advisory Council, 1985 November 13 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Philadelphia Metropolitan Library Council: 3 letters between Edwin and C. W. David, 1942 February 28-April 22 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - The Philobiblon Club: Letters to Edwin from A. S. W. Rosenbach and J. H. Powell, 1933 December 9, 1953 January 17 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - The Philobiblon Club: Speech delivered by George Allen (President) in honor of Edwin Wolf II, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - The Philobiblon Club: “In Honor of EW2," address given by George Allen, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Princeton Print Club: Invitation and membership card, 1941 May 19 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Clippings on the Rosenbach collection, 1943 December 22 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Rosenbach Fellowship: University of Pennsylvania News Bureau release regarding reciept of the award by Edwin, circa 1963 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Sesquicentennial Committee: Copy of the minutes from the 1971 September 8 meeting, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Society of American Historians: Letter to Edwin from Coutland Canby; brochure announcing a new publication, Magazine of World History, 1950 May 18, undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - University of Pennsylvania: Announcement and brochure for the 1967 April 22-27 antique show (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - University of Pennsylvania Library and Mrs. Theodore Dreiser: 12 letters between Edwin and C. W. David concerning various matters, especially the final acquisition of the Dreiser collection by the Van Pelt Library Rare Book Room, 1949 February 22-December 28 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - University of Pennsylvania Press: Letter to Edwin from J. Barnheim; accounts of press for 1967-1969; past guidelines for future press operation; report of the University Press Council, 1968 October 22, 1969 June 20, undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Poster for event at Mather House, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous civic activities: Reports on “History of Philadelphia” project and Cultural Recreation Task Force; citation for work with the Mayoral Cultural Advisory Council; letter to Edwin from the U.S. Department of Interior and accompanying The Restoration and Refurbishing of the First Floor of Independence Hall, 1954 September 27, 1972, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous organizations: Letters, bulletins, and schedules relating to Art Alliance, Free Library of Philadelphia, Philadelphia Cotillion, Colophon, Philmont Country Club, Antiquarian Booksellers of Philadelphia, Conference on American Colonial History, Radcliffe College, Philadelphia Arts Festival, Cosmopolitan Club, Committee of Humanities and Sciences, University of Pennsylvania Law School, Bibliographical Society of America, American Association for the History of Medicine, Rare Books and Manuscripts Section of the Association of College and Research Libraries, 1935 April 19-1988 June 14 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous organizations: 8 letters relating to The Smithsonian, American Antiquarian Society, Library of Congress, Free Library of Philadelphia, Philadelphia Club, PENN Club, U.S. Department of the Interior, and the Historical Society of Pennsylvania, 1975 August 6-1983 November 29 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous organizations: Letters to Edwin from L. M. C. Smith, R. Hirsch, and G. S. McManus, 1952 April 16, 1953 April 4, 1953 June 7 (Box 9, Folder 39)
- III. Scholarship, Bulk, 1945-1988; 1833-1996
  - IIIa. Talks and Publications, Bulk, 1960-1988; 1895-1990
    - Talk: "Spoon Feeding Researchers", 1963 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Talk: "Dear Sir or Madam", 1984 November 15 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Publication: "America's First Museum", 1981 August (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Talk: "Books as Physical Objects", 1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Talk: "Chestnut Street: The Metamorphosis of a Rialto", undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Talk: Untitled (on poetry), 1976 May (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Talk: Untitled (on William Blake), 1957 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Publication: "Blake Exhibitions in America", 1957 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Publication: Book reviews of Major Writers of Early American Literature and Men of Letters in Colonial Maryland, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Publication: Book review of John Carter Brown Library, The, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Talk/Publication: "Black Americana: A New World of Books", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Talk: "Bibliolatry Has Its Own Trinity", 1966 July 13 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Publication: "Exhibition of the Books Printed, Published and Bound by Robert Aitken, An", 1961 January 10 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Publication: "Broad Street", 1978 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Publication: "First Draft of the Constitution, The", 1962 September (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Publication: "By Love Possessed" (letter), 1957 October 1 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Talk/Publication: "Creating An Image", 1986 April (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Talk: "Decorating the Mind", circa 1961 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Talk: "Decorating the Mind", 1975 February (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Talk/Publication: "John Dickinson, Forgotten Patriot", 1968 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Talk: "Watercolors of Benjamin Ridgeway Evans", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Talk/Publication: "Evidence Indicating the Need for Some Bibliographical Analysis of American-Printed Historical Works", 1969 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Publication: "The Library Company's Air-Pump", undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Publication: "Reconstruction of Benjamin Franklin's Library: An Unorthodox Jigsaw Puzzle", 1962 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Publication: "Benjamin Franklin", undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Publication: "Flock of Beautiful Birds, A: The Ornithological Collection of Louise Elkins Sinkler", 1977 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Publication: "Library of Allegheny College (Meadville, Pa.), The" (1 of 2), circa 1963 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Publication: "Library of Allegheny College (Meadville, Pa.), The" (2 of 2), circa 1963 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Publication: "Year After Franklin's Year, The", 1957 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Talk/Publication: "Franklin's Philadelphia Institutions", 1980 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Publication: "Key to the Identification of Franklin's Books, A", 1956 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Publication: "'Doctor' Franklin", 1963 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Talk/Publication: "We Are a Kind of Posterity in Respect to Them", 1986, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Talk/Publication: "Sundry Printed Books", 1986, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Talk/Publication: "Lawyers and Law Books", 1986, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Talk/Publication: "Books For Large People and Small", 1986, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Talk/Publication: "They Lived History", 1986, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Publication: "Frustration and Benjamin Franklin's Medical Books", 1986 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Publication: "Private Franklin, The: The Man and His Family", 1976 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Publication: "German Jewish Influence on Philadelphia's Jewish Charities", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Publication: "Origins of Early American Printing Shops", 1978 July (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Publication: "Historical Grist for the Bibliographical Mill", 1972 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Talk/Publication: "In the Eye of the Beholder: European Book Illustrations of North America", undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Talk/Publication: "Philadelphia Disappointed", circa 1951 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Publication: "Library of Ralph Assheton", 1964 (Box 11, Folder 3)